>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 现在，我们终于开始谈论模块模式了。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Now, we finally get
to talk about the module pattern.
我们通过对词法范围的深入理解来建立自己。
We've built ourselves up through
a solid understanding of lexical scope.
词法范围让我们了解关闭工作的方式，以及
Lexical scope gives us an understanding
of how closure works, and
然后，关闭是了解模块模式的必需组件。
closure then is a necessary component
to understand the module pattern.
在查看模块模式是什么之前，
Before we look at what
the module pattern is,
我们需要看看模块模式是什么
we need to look at what
the module pattern is not.
这是一个非常常见的模式，一种常见的模式，
This is an extremely common pattern,
a common pattern where you have a set of
行为相似的函数以及这些函数所运行的数据集。
behavior-like functions and a set of
data that those functions operate on.
你想把它们一起收集到一些逻辑单元中最简单的方法就是
And you wanna collect them together into
some logical unit, the simplest way is to
只需创建对象并将您的数据和函数直接放在对象上。
just make an object and put your data and
your functions directly on the object.
我想说这个名字是非正式的但是
I would say that this has a name,
unofficially, but
它的名称为模式，这是名称空间模式。
this had a name as a pattern,
this is the namespace pattern.
获取一组功能和数据并将其放入对象中，
Taking a set of functions and data and
putting them inside of an object,
将它们作为属性而不是变量，
putting them as properties
instead of variables,
它有效地将它们收集到一个名称空间中。
it is effectively collecting
them into a namespace.
不是语言的语法功能，但是
Not really a syntactic
feature of the language, but
我们用物体来命名空间是一个独特的问题
it's an idiom that we make
namespaces with objects.
多年来，这是一个非常普遍的模式。
And for years,
this was an extremely common pattern.
这就是人们一起收集功能的方式。
This is how people collected
functionality together.
这是原始的数据结构，如果您愿意的话。
This was sort of the primitive
data structure, if you will.
这一特定模式没有任何错误。
Nothing wrong with this
particular pattern.
我在很多场合都用过
I've used it on many occasions.
你可能在自己的代码里看到过
You've probably seen it in your own code.
但我告诉你，绝对是 100% ，而不是一个模块。
But i would tell you it is definitely,
100%, positively not a module.
它不是模块的原因是模块模式
And the reason it's not a module
is that the module pattern
需要封装的概念。
requires the concept of encapsulation.
封装是一个时髦的 CS 词汇。
Encapsulation is a fancy sounding CS word.
所有这些都是隐藏数据和行为的想法。
All it really means is the idea
of hiding data and behavior.
这一切的意义在于不仅是我一起收集的
All it really means is,
not only have I collected it together,
这就是名称空间所创造的但我需要一些隐藏的概念
which is what the namespace creates,
but I need some notion of hiding,
一些关于信息隐藏的想法，或者一些对可视性的控制。
some idea for information hiding,
or some control over visibility.
一个模块，一个模块的概念，就是有一些东西是公开的，
A module, the idea of a module,
is that there are things that are public,
那是你的公共空气污染物而且有些东西是私人的
that's your public API, and
there are things that are private,
外面没人能碰的东西
that's things that nobody
on the outside can touch.
有一个可视性的概念，即使唯一的可视性概念要么是公共的，要么是
There's an idea of visibility, even if the
only visibility notion is either public or
私人的，还是封装这个概念的一个咒语。
private, that is still an incantation
of the idea of encapsulation.
所以如果你想有个模块你得有封装
So if you wanna have a module,
you gotta have encapsulation,
你得把数据藏起来
you gotta have data hiding.
在这里我们可以清楚地看到
And here,
we can clearly see that the properties and
它的功能是公开的，所以它不是一个模块。
functions that exist are public,
therefore it's not a module.
所以我们可以在这个概念上，或者在这个技术上，
So we can take this same idea and layer
on the idea, or layer on the technique
把信息隐藏起来我们都突然成为了一个模块
of encapsulation of information hiding,
and we all of the sudden make it a module.
让我们来看看这看起来是什么样的。
So let's look at what that looks like.
经典模块模式，有时称为显示模块
The classic module pattern, sometimes
referred to as the revealing module
模式，封装数据，完成封装。
pattern, it encapsulates data and
it does so with closure.
那是关键
That's key.
所以你不能有一个模块，如果你没有关闭的话。
So you can't have a module,
if you don't have closure.
这是不可能的好吗
It's just not possible, okay?
就连我们在概念上讲的 F6 模块，
Even the F6 modules, which we will talk
about in a little bit, conceptually,
我们得把它们当作封闭物
we need to think about them as closure.
模块模式，第一类编码为经典或
The module pattern,
first sort of codified as the classic or
显示模块模式。
the revealing module pattern.
2001 年被 Doug Crawford 编纂成法
It was codified by
Doug Crawford-ish in 2001,
这就是它看起来的样子
and this is kinda what it looks like.
它有两个组成部分。
It has two components to it.
第一，我们有一个外层的封闭功能。
Number one,
we have an outer enclosing function.
在这种情况下，它是一个 IIFE，每个人都在那里看到 IIFE 吗 ?
In this case, it's an IIFE,
everybody see the IIFE there?
它是个 IIFE
It's an IIFE, and
当我们把一个模块作为一个 IIF 的时候，就好像说它是一个单体。
when we run a module as an IIFE, that's
kind of like saying it's a singleton.
因为我们知道 IIFEs 运行一次
Since we know IIFEs run once and
然后他们就这样做了这就像一个单身人士
then they're done,
this is sort of like a singleton.
它运行一次，然后就完成了，除了在空中的引用意义上，
It runs once, and then it's done,
except done only in the air quote sense,
因为封闭会阻止这个范围的消失
because the closure is gonna
prevent that scope from going away.
第二个组成部分就是我们有一个内在的功能，
The second component then,
is that we have an inner function,
在这个案件中询问第七条关于这些变量的情况
in this case ask on line 7,
that is closed over those variables,
在这种情况下，它是通过教师变量关闭的。
in this case,
it is closed over the teacher variable.
因为它已经关闭了老师的变量
Since it's closed over
the teacher variable,
外部的工作坊对象，现在已经参考了这个功能，
the workshop object on the outside,
which has now reference to that function,
通过封闭保持内部范围。
is preserving that inner
scope through closure.
问老师结束了，我们在外面说 workshop.ask ，
Ask is closed over teacher, and
when we say workshop.ask on the outside,
那就是范围没把垃圾收起来，那个范围还在，
that's scope didn't get garbage collected
and go away, that scope is still there,
那个国家还在那里，这就是我们的效果
that state is still there,
and that's how we effect or
在 JavaScript中创建模块模式，模块模式的 idiom 。
create the module pattern,
the idiom of module pattern in JavaScript.
我们把自己的私事公布于私事让我们暴露在一个物体上
We keep our private state private,
and we expose things on an object,
就像我在这里做的公共 API 对象一样
like what I'm doing here
with the public API object.
我只是在揭露你的要求
Is I'm exposing only the ask function.
但我能有很多私人的功能
But I could have hundreds of other
functions that were private,
无法从外部访问的信息。
that could not be accessed
from the outside.
但封闭功能能让他们一整天都能进入
And yet the closure functions
can access them all day long,
如果他们想的话就会被封锁
if they want to, because of closure.
我可以说 workshop.ask ，但我不能说workshop.老师。
So I can say workshop.ask, but
I can't say workshop.teacher.
老师藏起来了
Teacher is hidden.
滚吧
Roll that.
>> Kyle Simpson: 结束不作为。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's closure inaction.
它只是上百个可能关闭的应用程序中的一个。
It's only one of hundreds of
possible applications of closure.
但我们无法用这种方式完成模块模式。
But we couldn't do the module
pattern in this way.
我们不可能影响到把信息隐藏起来的这个想法
We couldn't affect this idea of
information hiding of encapsulation
在没有关闭的情况下
without closure.
>> Kyle Simpson: 此处识别的关键是使用
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: What's critical to
recognize here is that this usage of
关闭实际上正在关闭设计为更改状态的变量
closure is actually closing over variables
that are designed to change state
随着时间的推移
over time.
这就是一个模块的目的，它是在一段时间内跟踪状态。
That's the whole purpose of a module,
is to track state over time.
事实上，我想说的是，如果你有一个叫模块的东西，
In fact, I'd go so far as to say, if you
have a thing that you call a module,
它没有任何国家，或者说
and it doesn't have any state, or rather,
它没有任何改变的状态它不是一个模块
it doesn't have any state that
ever changes, it's not a module.
这只是一个过度设计的名称空间，好吗 ?
It's just an over-engineered namespace,
okay?
模块的用途是您已关闭了某些状态，并且
The purpose of a module is that you have
some state that you're closed over, and
通过公开最低公共 API 来控制对其的访问。
you are controlling access to it
by exposing a minimal public API.
还记得最少曝光特权的原则吗
Remember that principle of
least exposure privilege?
这就在这里
That's in action here.
我们是说把一切都藏起来
We're saying keep everything hidden,
除了最低限度暴露在外面的必要
except minimally expose only
what's necessary on the outside.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是这里的想法。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's the idea here.
尽量少暴露需要的东西。
Minimally expose only what's necessary.
这是模块模式。
That's the module pattern.
现在，上一张幻灯片有一个模块 IIFE， AKA，一个模块单体。
Now, the previous slide had a module IIFE,
AKA, a module singleton.
但这不是制造模块的唯一方法。
But that's not the only
way to make modules.
我们可以只做多次可以调用的常规函数。
We can make just regular functions
that can be called multiple times.
每次都有一个函数
And every time a function is called,
它会产生我们模块的新实例
it's gonna produce a new
instance of our module.
我们把这些都称为工厂的功能，好吗 ?
We lovingly refer to those
as factory functions, okay?
这是车间模块工厂功能。
This is a workshop
module factory function.
我可以打一次就像我在 12 号线上一样但我可以给它打上百次电话
I can call it once, like I do on line 12,
but I could call it a hundred other times
还有一百个单独的例子，都有各自的国家。
and have a hundred other separate
instances that all have their own state.
它们都是分开的而且不会相互混合
They're all separate and
they don't mix with each other.
这是果壳中的模块模式。
And that is the module
pattern in a nutshell.
我的意思是我有一些行为
The idea that I take some behavior, and
该行为对其进行操作，并将其封装到数据结构中。
data that that behavior operates on, and
encapsulate it into a data structure.
隐藏我不需要显示的内容，并仅显示最低必需的 API。
Hide what I don't need to show, and
expose only the minimal necessary API.
那是个模块
That's a module.
我认为模块模式肯定是最普遍的
And I would argue that the module
pattern is certainly the most prevalent,
并且可能是所有代码组织模式中最重要的。
and potentially the most important
of all code organization patterns.
八成是所有被写的 JavaScript 的 90%
Probably 80, 90% of all JavaScript
that's ever been written
已使用诸如模块模式之类的机制作为其代码组织模式。
has used some mechanism like the module
pattern as it's code organization pattern.
这不是说你没有其他的模式，比如类，但是
That's not to say you don't have other
patterns, like classes, for example, but
模块模式极其普遍和重要，并且
the module pattern is extremely
prevalent and important, and
重要的是我们要了解它是如何运作的
it's important that we
understand how it works.
现在，让我们都承认这是一种句法式的黑客行为，这并不是真的，
Now, let's all admit that this is sort of
a syntactic hack, this is not really like,
你就不会给这个模块用这个第一类语言支持了。
you wouldn't really call this first
class language support for a module.
你会把这称为 " 成语" 是我们使用的模式
You would call this an idiom,
a pattern that we do using
工具以实现一些最终目的。
the tools in a way that
accomplishes some end goal.